Finding Aid for the Jean Renoir Papers PASC.0105
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Part I - Production Files
  - Series V: PUBLICATIONS (Books) BY JEAN RENOIR
    - RENOIR [PIERRE-AUGUSTE]
      - - Text, "Preface pour l'Exposition Renoir, Dalzell Hatfield Galleries, 9/15/43," 4 typed pages, dated 8/30/43. - Remarks prepared in conjunction with exhibit, 1 typed page (2 copies), n.d. (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - - Text of speech, "Conference d'un conferencier americain devant l'union francaise," 6 typed pages, marked "c. 1942." (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - - Typescript, "Conference de Jean Renoir a la Radio le 25 Novembre 1941," 6 pages. - Newspaper clipping, "La Maison de Renoir," dated 8/12/60. (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - - "Notes pour le conference de Jean Renoir a l'Alliance Francaise de Los Angeles," 7 pages (2 copies), 1/19/42. (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - - Typed, annotated drafts of article for Life Magazine: - 11/7/50 version, 12 pages each (2 copies). - 11/12/50 version, 11 pages. - 1/12/51 versions, 4 and 5 pages. - 1/15/51 version, 4 pages. (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - - Carbon typescript, "Renoir, le Siecle, et Moi," 4 pages (2 copies), n.d. (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - - "Au temps de Mon Pere," 4 typed, annotated pgs, 3/25/42. - Revision, "Chapitre I," annotated carbon, 6 pgs + frag., n.d. - "Souvenirs de Collettes" (version for Time Magazine), 3/10/47. - "My Happy Father" (English translation), 8 pgs and 7 pgs. (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - - "Peindre ou marcher," 7 typed, annotated pgs (2 copies), n.d. - "To Paint or to Walk," typed "correction," 6 pgs (2 copies) + cover letter fr/ transl, 1/21/1942. - Engl. trans, 4 copies (2 re-titled "The Miracle"), 4 pgs ea, n.d (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - - Various drafts and reworkings of "Au Temps de Mon Pere," dating 3/18/42 - 5/11/43. (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - - Typed, annotated pages, "Introduction [to Memoirs]," 5 pages each (2 copies), 5/6/43. - Typed pages, "Chapitre I [subtitled 'Jeunesse de Renoir']," 8 pages, (?)5/6/43. (Box 76, Folder 14)
      - - Notes and fragments, 3 items, circa 2/25/60 (?). - Two notebooks: one marked "Notes sur livre Renoir," the other "Renoir - conclusions," circa 1954. (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - - Notebook marked "Renoir," dated 6/9/??. (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - - Notebook, marked "Renoir - Achat des Collettes," October 1956. (Box 76, Folder 17)
      - - Notebook, marked "Renoir: Notes," incl. 2-page ms. insert, n.d [missing pages]. - Side-spiralbound notebook ("suite de 259+"), n.d. - 2 small notebooks, 1 topbound, the other (sidebound) marked "Notes" - Loose pgs/extract, 47 pages, 1/17/58. (Box 76, Folder 18)
      - - Clipping, "P.-A. Renoir repose en terre d'Essoyes," by P. Croyes, source and date unknown. (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - Series VI: ESSAYS AND ARTICLES BY JEAN RENOIR
    - unspecified
      - - Transcribed essays by and interviews with J.R. (accompanying note: "textes a approuver pour publication"), 1930's - 1950's. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - - Various handwritten essays, including "Rue Caulaincourt," n.d. (Box 13, Folder 52)
      - - Song lyrics and poems, on typed and handwritten pages: - "Chanson du Carrefour." - "Complainte." - "Opera" [fragment]. - Many untitled compositions, 23 pages, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - - "Sans Titre" [essay re the artist, progress, consumerism, and related topics]. - Typed pages, 2 pages (2 copies) n.d. - Handwritten pages, 41 pages, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - - Miscellaneous pages recording J.R.'s ideas and thoughts on a variety of subjects. Handwritten. 15 pages. (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - - Notebook pages w/ several essays/projects: "L'Actrice," "Le Diable," "Le Sexe," "Dialogues dans L'Au-dela/L'Autre-monde/L'Ange Gabriel." 32 pages. (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - - Notebook pages with handwritten notes on for several projects. 44 pages total. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - - Loose pages, personal writings, some dated: 16 May 1971, 16 May 1972. (1) dated 12 November 1970, (1) dated 6 May 1971, (1) n.d. [several decades earlier]. Notes from the Scripps Clinic, Lo Jolla, California. (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - - Notebook dated 18 June, 1961, includes "Assassinat de jeune premier." (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - - Notebook, entitled "Propos" (main character Wladimir Waltz), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - - Synopsis of novels: "Notes dictated by J. R. to Dido Freire," spanning February 1941 through 1947(?), 52 handwritten, 1 typed page. - Detailed "Resume d'un roman" ("Le Moulier"), original and copy, 12 pages each, dated 4/18/34. Author unknown. (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - - "Prologue," dated 7/2/75 and 2/18/76, 2 pages (2 copies). (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - - Two notebooks: one dated "fin fevrier, 1945," one entitled "projets." (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - - Individual pages, along with several short pieces (incl. "Je me reveille.."), 26 handwritten pages. n.d. (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - - Partial manuscript, pages 21-54, 38 pages, n.d. (Main characters are Simone and Emmanuel) (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - - Two unidentified notebooks, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - - Notebook, c. 1968. Includes: "La Loi de Mann," "Le Fruit Pouri," "Reflexions, souvenirs, d'un faiseur de films." (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - - Notebook, n.d. Includes "La Peche," "La Reunion," "Melez vous de ce que vous regarde." Also includes numerous drawings. (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - - Introduction to exhibition pamphlet for show by Etienne Ret, Dalzell Hatfield Galleries, Los Angeles, California, 2/6-2/28/?? (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - 1952
      - - "Cahiers du Cinema" Renoir Issue, no. 8, Jan. 1952: "On me demande," pp. 5-8, and "Quelque chose m'est arrive," pp. 31-32. (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - ANDRE, ALBERT
      - - Article "Albert Andre," with note, "Article pour une exposition Albert Andre a la Galerie Guiot," 1 page, 10/12/60. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - ART APPRECIATION..
      - - J.R.'s preface to Lee Siegel Jr.'s book, "Art Appreciation For Grown-ups Under Ten," 2 pages, 8/13/66. (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - BAZIN, ANDRE
      - - Preface by J.R. to Andre Bazin's "Qu-est-ce que le Cinema?" - Preface by J.R. to Bazin's "Jean Renoir,"2 copies, 1971. - Tribute by J.R. entitled "Andre Bazin Notre Conscience," 2 pages, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - BECKER, JACQUES
      - - Article for "Cahiers du Cinema," "Au Revoir, Jacques," 2 pages, 3/4/60, 1 page, 3/6/60. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - LA BETE HUMAINE
      - - Notes by J.R. for a talk given at the annual meeting of "La Societie de Zola" at the Sorbonne, November 1939. (Box 13, Folder 42)
      - - "A Propos de la Bete Humaine," by J.R. 3 pages, including 1 handwritten copy, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - BOUDU SAUVE DES EAUX
      - - Prefatory remarks by J.R. at screening by U.C. Santa Barbara Film Society, Santa Barbara, California, January 8, 1967. 2 pages. (Box 13, Folder 41)
      - - "How I Came to Film 'Boudu'," in Film Society Review, February 1967, p. 23. (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - C'EST LA REVOLUTION
      - - "Mon oncle Emmanuel..": 5 drafts, 30 handwritten pages total, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - LE CAPORAL EPINGLE
      - - Article written by J.R., labeled "sent to Duncan McGregor," 3 pages, 2/15/63. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - CHAPLIN, CHARLIE
      - - Articles about Charlie Chaplin and LIMELIGHT. 3 pages. n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - - Article, "Chaplin Among the Immortals," for "The Screen Writer" magazine, July 1947, 3 copies in English, 4 copies in French. (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - CHASSEZ LE NATUREL
      - - Article written at the request of Claude Beylie, "Chassez le naturel..," 1 page, 8/7/78. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - LES COMEDIENS
      - - Article for the journal DU, Zurich. January 17, 1967. 2 pages, 2 copies. (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - - "La Comedia Dell'arte," 23 pages, in English, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - LE CRIME DE MONSIEUR LANGE
      - - Article, "Souvenirs," with note "envoye a Brandon, N.Y.," 3 pages, 3/15/61. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - DIRECTIONS AND RECIPES
      - - Typescript pages, entitled "Directions and Recipes - Version II," 3 pages total, 7/20/46. (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - DREYER, CARL-THEODORE
      - - Critical appreciation/reminiscence re Carl-Th. Dreyer, "La peche de Dreyer," pp. 41-45. (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - ELENA ET LES HOMMES
      - - " Jean Renoir et Venus": annotated album notes explicating the film's music. 2 copies, 13 pages, n.d., one copy 9 pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - LES FILMS SONT-ILS UN ART OU UNE INDUSTRIE?
      - - Article for the Screen Producers Guild Journal, handwritten and typed pages, 14 pages, 12/23/63, with accompanying correspondence. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - FLAHERTY, ROBERT
      - - Handwritten page, entitled "Robert Flaherty" (n.d.). (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - GODDEN, RUMER
      - - Article: "Jean Renoir, A Propos De Rumer Godden," 1 page (carbon), 8/28/63. (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - - Article, "Rumer Godden," for the Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc., 10/1-10/17/50. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - LA GRANDE ILLUSION
      - - "Texte de la bande annonce dit par J.R." 2 copies, n.d. 4 pages each. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - - Various drafts, typed w/ manuscript changes. - Note: "Envoye a Georges Sadoul, le 20 Mars 1948." (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - - [La Grande Illusion] and [La Marseillaise], 4 pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - HISTOIRE DU CANNIBALISM..
      - - "Histoire du cannibalism et da la diminution de la population d'une colonie," typed original and copy, 2 pages each, plus 1 handwritten title sheet, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - IN WHAT WAY CAN A FILM BE INTERNATIONAL?
      - - Manuscript of an article solicited by United Nations publication, "In What Way Can A Film Be International?", 10 pages, 3 copies, in English, December 1952-January 1953. - Reply/correspondence from the magazine, March 1953. (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - J'AI 80 ANS
      - - "J'ai 80 Ans" ("I Am Eighty"), rough drafts of the article in manuscript and typescript (some carbon pages), in French and English, 41 pages, 8/21-8/27/74. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - JAUBERT, MAURICE
      - - Poem by J.R., "Jean Renoir a Maurice Jaubert," 6/18/54. (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - LES JEUX FUNEBRES
      - - 2 drafts, of 9 and 13 handwritten pages, respectively, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - LAEMMLE, CARL
      - - Poem/homage written by J.R. to Carl Laemmle, Jr., 1 page, 10/21/65. (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - LANGLOIS, HENRI
      - - Article, "Hommage to Henri Langlois," for "Filmex," 1 page, 3/2/77. (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - LEWIN, ALBERT
      - - Article on Albert Lewin, with second draft, 3 pages, 2/11/66-5/10/68. Incl. a poem by Albert Lewin. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - LOURIE, EUGENE
      - - Exhibition program for show by Eugene Lourie, with introduction by J.R., for the American Contemporary Gallery, Los Angeles, California, September 1944. (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - LA MARSEILLAISE
      - - [La Grande Illusion] and [La Marseillaise]. 4 pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 45)
      - - Essay ["a propos du film "La Marseillaise"], 1 page (carbon), 5/18/44. (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - A MODERN PARABLE
      - - "A Modern Parable ['..are films an art or an industry?']" in: "The Journal of the Screen Producers Guild, March 1964, pp. 3-6. in: The Journal of the Producers Guild of America, 10th Anniversary Anthology, pp. 5-8. (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - NOTRE TEMPS..
      - - "Notre temps c'est celui du succes..": 2 drafts, handwritten, 3 and 2 pages, respectively, 5/15/63. - "Histoires d'Amour," handwritten, 1 page, 5/15/63. (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - PAGNOL, MARCEL
      - - Article, "Marcel Pagnol," w/ note: "ecrit a la demande de Claude Beylie," 1 page, 10/24/73. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - LE PARAGON
      - - "Le Paragon": 9 handwritten pages, n.d. - "Projet April 1960": 2 handwritten notebook pages. (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - UNE PARTIE DE CAMPAGNE
      - - Essay written by J.R., in English, 4 pages, 11/29/50. (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - PICASSO AND CO.
      - - J.R.'s review of the book, "Picasso and Co," handwritten/annotated and typed ms. pages, in French and English, 60 pages, October 1966. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - - Book review of "Picasso and Company" by Brassai, 1946. (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - PREVERT, JACQUES
      - - "Jean Renoir sur Jacques Prevert," 2 pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - QUELQUE CHOSE D'IMPORTANT M'EST ARRIVE
      - - "Quelque chose d'important m'est arrive..," 3 pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - REFLEXIONS SUR STANISLAVSKI
      - - Article, "Reflexions sur Stanislavski" (pour "L'Art du Cinema" - Moscou), 1 page (carbon), 10/27/62. (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - - Article, "Reflexions," for the Benedictine Brothers, 2 pages, 2 copies, 10/17/63. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - REINIGER, LOTTE
      - - "A propos de Lotte Reiniger." Introduction for Paul Gelder's book on Lotte Reiniger, "Out of the Shadows," 8 pages, various drafts, 4/30/77. (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - ROSSELLINI, ROBERTO
      - - Article "Rossellini," with handwritten note, "article envoye a Pierre Lherminier," 1 page, 2/23/63. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - SAINT-EXUPERY, ANTOINE
      - - Article about Antoine de Saint-Exupery, "Il Parlait Toute La Nuit," 4 pages, dated 1977. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - SESONSKE, ALEXANDER
      - - J.R.'s corrections of A. Sesonske's chapter re "The Grand Illusion," with accompanying correspondence, 40 pgs, 9/10/74. - Copy of Sesonke's chapter re "1944: A Salute to France," 17 pgs, n.d. - J.R.'s preface to A. Sesonske's book, 1 pg, 12/77. (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - SICARD, PIERRE
      - - Introduction by J.R. for an exhibition of paintings by Pierre Sicard, in Los Angeles, 3 pages, 12/28/50. Includes (2) gallery brochures. - Article, "Pierre Sicard," dated 12 August, 1963, 4 pages. (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - SIMENON, GEORGES
      - - "Simenon," 2 pages, February 1961. (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - SIMON, MICHEL
      - - "Michel Simon - Il Est Vivant," 13 pages, 2 copies, 12/23/74. (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - TEXT OF SPEECHES
      - - Transcript of "Recorded greeting for the Annual Women's Day of the Soviet Union - March 8, 1944." 2 pages, 3 copies, 2/25/44. (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - - Text of a speech to the League of American Writers, in English, 7 pages, 2 copies, 4/23/43. (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - - Text of a speech recorded by J.R. to be broadcast to North Africa, 7 pages, 7 copies, December 1942-January 1943. (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - - Text of an unspecified talk [re artistic future of the cinema], 13 pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - - Text of speech delivered at the Museum of Modern Art (in conjunction with "A Short Survey of the Film in America: The Development of Narrative, 1895-1912"), MOMA Film Library, New York, 8/6/1943. Two copies in French, two copies in English. (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - - Transcription of a tape made in Beverly Hills, 2/10/58, for "L'Hommage a Jean Renoir," at La Grande Amphitheatre de la Sorbonne, 4 pages. (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - TIME MAGAZINE
      - - Project/article marked for "Time Magazine," two versions: 3 pages and 8 pages (3/3/47). (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - LA VANITE
      - - Typewritten notes, "L'Vanite": - 1-page statement/synopsis. - 2-page version, original and copy, 4/12/42. - 4-page version, original and copy, 4/13/42. (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - VENICE FILM FESTIVAL
      - - Handwritten notes about Venice Film Festival, 1968. (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - LE VIEUX MONSIEUR
      - - Two typed pages, dated 6-2-75. 2 copies. (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - LES VIVANTS ET LES MORTS
      - - Notebook, 5 pages, entitled "Notes-Research", 3 typed pages and 12 handwritten pages. (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Series VII: NOTEBOOKS
    - unspecified
      - - Notebook pages with several essays/projects, n.d. Includes "L'Actrice," "Le Diable," "Le Sexe," "Dialogues dans L'Au-dela/L'Autre monde/L'Ange Gabriel." 32 pages total. (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - - Notebook pages with handwritten notes on plans for several projects. 44 pages total. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - - Notebook dated 18 June, 1961, includes "Assassinat de jeune premier." (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - - Notebook, entitled "Propos" (main character Wladimir Waltz), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - - Two notebooks, one dated "fin Fevrier, 1945," one entitled "projets". (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - - Notebook, includes "La poursuite du bonheur," "Les Francais," and several other projects, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - - Notebook, c. 1968. Includes: "La Loi de Mann," "Le Fruit Pouri," "Reflexions, souvenirs, d'un faiseur de films." (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - - Notebook, n.d. Includes: "La Peche," "La Reunion," "Melez vous de ce que vous regarde." Also includes numerous drawings. (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - - Notebook, unidentified. (One of the main characters is Clemence). (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - - Two notebooks with handwritten notes and two handwritten pages dating from the time of J.R.'s service in the French Cinematographic Corps during World War II. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - L'ACTRICE
      - - Handwritten notes for project, 7/2/66. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - ADAM
      - - Side-spiralbound notebook, cover marked "Adam," dated c. 7/7/?year? (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - THE AMERICAN WAY
      - - Handwritten journal notes, 12-19 May (no year noted). (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - AMPHITRYON
      - - Five notebooks with handwritten notes, dated 4/12/48, 9/23/48, 1/7/49, 9/10 (no year given), 1/31/(no year given). (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - LES CAHIERS DU CAPITAINE GEORGES
      - - Four notebooks, incl. 2 spiralbound (on side), one commencing "L'amour et le grace," the other w/ date, 12/7/62. - Third (top-spiralbound) bgns w/ initial pages torn out, then "Le bonheur mesdames/cahier 3," n.d. Cover of 4th marked "Georges," n.d. (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - - Three notebooks, marked "No.3" and "1," "2," and "3," interleafed with typed and manuscript emendations and corrections, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - - Three notebooks, marked "1 - Volume I," "1 - Volume II," and "1 - Volume III." "1 - Volume I" contains sheaf of 11 typed pages with glossary of book's terms and handwritten notes/corrections. No date specified. (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - - Double-spiralbound notebook containing bound version of typescript, interleafed with typed pages and handwritten corrections and annotations. (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - REFLECTIONS ON CAROLA AND GENERAL MEDITATIONS
      - - Three notebooks containing J.R.'s thoughts on "Carola" and related musings. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - - Side-spiralbound notebook, first page of which marked (at top) "Carola 4 avril [n.d.]." (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - - Spiral top-bound notebook marked "Carola," with notes concerning play's production, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - LA CHASSE AU BONHEUR
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - CHRSITINE
      - - Notebook. Forward entries on CHRISTINE, starting from the end notes on ROSALIE. Also includes a few pages each on MES REVES and LA TOSCA (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - LE COEUR A L'AISE
      - - Four spiralbound notebooks, three of which are marked "L'Acteur 75." Dates of entries range from approx. 7/11/75 ("#0") through 7/29/75 ("#1") to 9/11/75 ("#2"). (Box 61, Folder unknown container)
    - LE CRIME DE L'ANGLAIS
      - - Two side-spiralbound notebooks, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - - Two notebooks with dictated notes, "Notes Sur la Cheze-Dieu," February 1977. - 1 notebook titled (first page) "Le Crime de le Chaise-Dieu," n.d. (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - LA CROIX DE MALTE
      - - Handwritten notes in notebook, 42 pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - LE DEJEUNER SUR L'HERBE (1959)
      - - Two handwritten notebooks, one denoted "Dejeuner," the other "Dejeuner 1/1/59" and "Nouveau Project, 11 August 1959." (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - LE DELUGE
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, dated November 1947 (also includes commencement of additional project, "Les Ours en Cage," dated 11/28/47). (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - LES DEMI-REVES
      - - Notebook, marked with name of project and "Notes," n.d. First 10 pages nearly completely excised. (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - L'EDUCATION DES FILLES
      - - Four notebooks with handwritten notes, one dated 12/1/56. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - ELENA ET LES HOMMES (1956)
      - - Notebook entitled "Generalites." (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - LES FRANCAIS
      - - Two notebooks, undated, one side-spiralbound, inside front page marked "Les Francais". (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - FRENCH CANCAN (1954)
      - - Handwritten notebook entitled "Cancan" ("Gaspard" and "Idees" at other end, inverted). Includes notes and sketches for "Gaspard," "La Lutte contre les Conventions," and "Rosario." Total 24 pgs. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - LA GUERRE ET APRES
      - - Handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - JUDITH
      - - Handwritten notes, dated 8/22/56. (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - LE JUGEMENT DERNIER
      - - Notebook, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - JULIE
      - - Notebook, 11/26/56. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - - Notebook, marked "L'assassinat du jeune premier" across front, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - LANCELOT
      - - Notebook, incl. notes for other projects, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - LES LETTRES D'UN MILLIONAIRE
      - - Notebook, marked "Le Journal d'un Millionaire," c. 1/15/41. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - LUCIE
      - - Two notebooks, one maked "Lucie" and "L. Doynal" on front, n.d. the other marked "Lulu" and "Resume du 2 janvier au milieu de cahier," n.d. (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - MA VIE ET MES FILMS
      - - Two spiralbound notebooks, one with cover marked "Cinema," the other commencing with "Souvenirs d'un faiseur de films," c. 1/5/70. (Box 71, Folder 12)
      - - Notebook, marked "Adam" on cover, incl. notes re "Souvenirs de un faiseur des films," c. 8/6/70. (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - MIRACLE
      - - Five notebooks, December 31, 1959 - February 5, 1960. (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - ORVET
      - - Three notebooks, dated November 1954, February 8 (1955?), and October 21 (1954?) (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - LE PETIT THEATRE DE JEAN RENOIR (1969)
      - - Notebook, marked "C'est la Revolution," n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - RENOIR [PIERRE-AUGUSTE]
      - - Side-spiralbound notebook, commencing with "Projet - Gabrielle," dated 9/29/46. (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - - Two notebooks: one marked "Notes sur livre Renoir," the other, "Renoir - conclusions," dating from c. 1954. (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - - Notebook, marked "Renoir," dated 6/9/??. (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - - Notebook, marked "Renoir - Achat des Collettes," October 1956. (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - SPARKE
      - - Notebook, marked "Sparke-1a cahier," 10 pages, c. 1930's. (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - TIBI
      - - Three notebooks, includes project sketches, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - VINCENT VAN GOGH
      - - Notebook, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Series VIII: WRITINGS ABOUT JEAN RENOIR
    - 1937
      - - Transcribed article, "Entretien Avec Jean Renoir," by Kawazoe Shiro, 7 pages, 10/21/37. (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - 1952
      - - "Cahiers du Cinema" J. R. Issue, no. 8, Jan. 1952. Incl: - A. Bazin, "Renoir Francais," pp. 9-29. - D. Nichols, "La Fleuve," p. 30. - M. Scherer, "Renoir Americain," pp. 33-40. - J. Doniol-Valcroze, "Entretien avec J.R.," pp. 48-51. - Filmography. (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - 1955
      - - Photographic illustrations of J.R., Jean Gabin, Marcel Pagnol, and other leading French film and intellectual figures of the 1950's, in Japanese movie magazine, "Eiga No Tomo ["Friend of Movies"]," vol. 23, no. 3, March 1955, p. 125. (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - 1956
      - - Outline for the "Omnibus" television program about J.R., 2 pages, 8/12/56. (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - 1957